Gene Basset Papers
Gene Basset Papers
- Cartoons, 1,319 items
  - Cartoons, 1964, Aug (Oversize 3)
    Aug 11: Just so we get equal credit: Democratic Party, Republican Party, civil rights
    Aug 12: Here it is, chief...just the way you ordered it: Lyndon B. Johnson, Congress, War on Poverty
    Aug 13: Follow the leader: Republican Party, Barry Goldwater
    Aug 14: Manned bomber: Curtis LeMay, Barry Goldwater, Robert McNamara, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Aug 19: Out...damn sun spot: Barry Goldwater, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Aug 20: The sphinx speaks: Barry Goldwater, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Aug 29: I'm getting rid of an awful headache!: Vietnam War
    Aug 31: Political football: Congress, rural concerns, urban concerns
  - Cartoons, 1964, Sep (Oversize 3)
    Sep 1: One thing I promise...not to smear my dishonest, cynical, moronic opponent: elections
    Sep 2: Well Hello there: Mississippi, integration, schools
    Sep 4: Step right brother...plenty of room inside: Makarios III, Gamal Abdel Nasser, Nikita Khrushchev
    Sep 8: We shall overcome: Medicare, Lyndon B. Johnson, Congress
    Sep 9: Mr. President...if Senator Goldwater pulls that 'I shall go to 'Vietnam' bit...let him: Vietnam War, Barry Goldwater, Lyndon B. Johnson, Maxwell Taylor
    Sep 10: ...and another campaign contribution gratefully received…: auto industry, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Sep 11: Operation exhume: Bobby Baker, Democratic Party
    Sep 11: Class is now in session: George Wallace
    Sep 12: General Khanh...the Army awaits your orders: Vietnam War, Nguyen Khanh
    Sep 15: Officer...I'm trying to find a Democratic racially balanced school I've been ordered to attend: integration, schools
    Sep 16: But I just came from here: Medicare
    Sep 19: Camouflage: Lyndon B. Johnson, elections
    Sep 22: That'll teach'em you can't legislate morals: Mississippi, civil rights
    Sep 23: That sorta makes Hubert one of us: Hubert Humphrey
    Sep 25: Steady as she goes: Lyndon B. Johnson, elections
    Sep 26: Nuts...nothing but the facts!: Warren Commission
    Sep 28: Fashionable: Charles De Gaulle, South America
  - Cartoons, 1964, Oct (Oversize 4)
    Oct 2: I got the world on a string: Mao Zedong, nuclear weapons
    Oct 12: Why not victory?: Olympics
    Oct 13: Comrades, we've miscalculated...too many for chess and too few for bridge: space exploration
    Oct 14: I accuse!: Barry Goldwater
    Oct 17: As a nuclear power I say, ban the bombs: nuclear weapons, Mao Zedong
    Oct 19: Eternal: Herbert Hoover
    Oct 20: Headache: nuclear weapons
    Oct 22: Lip shootin': Barry Goldwater, Nikita Khrushchev, Lyndon B. Johnson, nuclear weapons, China
    Oct 24: Comrade Khrushchev, the no good bum...never heard of him: France, Italy, communism, Nikita Khrushchev
    Oct 26: Gas attack: elections
    Oct 27: We foresee no difficulties: Soviet Union, Alexey Kosygin, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev
    Oct 28: Sorry kid...no handouts: Barry Goldwater (intended for Halloween)
    Oct 30: Children's game: Barry Goldwater, communism, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Oct 31: Here are the first returns: elections (intended for the following Tuesday, election day)
  - Cartoons, 1964, Nov (Oversize 4)
    Nov 2: Welcome to our East Berlin paradise...did you bring food and clothing?: Berlin
    Nov 3: Inside job: Vietnam War
    Nov 5: Flotsam: Barry Goldwater, mainstream politics
    Nov 7: Rat fink: Barry Goldwater, Richard Nixon, Nelson Rockefeller
    Nov 11: A toast to Red China from her Soviet comrades: China, Soviet Union, Alexey Kosygin, Leonid Ilyich Brezhnev
    Nov 12: Kamikaze: traffic fatalities
    Nov 16: Fast rising dough: Bobby Baker
    Nov 18: Timberrrrrrrrrr: Congress
    Nov 23: Solar system: Charles De Gaulle
    Nov 24: Comforter: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Nov 25: Rough sea: France, Britain, nuclear weapons
    Nov 27: On to another massacre in the name of independence: Congo
    Nov 28: The odor seems to get stronger each day: Congress
    Nov 30: When's the next erruption due?: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson, Maxwell Taylor
  - Cartoons, 1964, Dec (Oversize 4)
    Dec 1: Strange Bedfellows: civil rights, Federal Bureau of Investigation, Ku Klux Klan
    Dec 2: Sc-c-cal P-p-pel: Bobby Baker
    Dec 3: Delayed action: United Nations, Soviet Union, U. Thant
    Dec 4: All I want for Christmas is some new front teeth: Republican Party
    Dec 8: We're doing everything known to medical science: Medicare
    Dec 9: What a way to go: Congress
    Dec 10: Hey, come back....wanna cost me my job?: Republican Party, Dean Burch
    Dec 16: Apollo, the after-burning reindeer: Christmas, space exploration
    Dec 17: Paris in the Winter: Dean Rusk, Charles De Gaulle, France
    Dec 19: Battleground: Republican Party, Dean Burch, Charles Halleck
    Dec 22: Whodunit: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Dec 24: Season's Greetings: Vietnam War
    Dec 24: Kickoff time at the Egyptian Bowl: Gamal Abdel Nasser
    Dec 30: As for running the labor department, you're getting too big for your breeches: AFL-CIO, George Meany, Willard Wirtz
    Dec 31: Help!: Congo, Lyndon B. Johnson
  - Cartoons, 1965, Jan (Oversize 4)
    Jan 4: They got-their nerve....jush cause (hic) we got high on (hic) Goldwater: Democratic Party
    Jan 5: Welcome to the Great Society!: Lyndon Johnson, Great Society
    Jan 7: He threatens to quit our club unless we coddle him: Sukarno, United Nations
    Jan 11: America the beautiful: pollution
    Jan 12: I bought the tools from the West: Soviet Union, Romania
    Jan 13: By majority vote I've been elected fall guy: Dean Burch, Republican Party, elections
    Jan 16: Imprint: Winston Churchill
    Jan 18: Great Society Inauguration: Lyndon B. Johnson, Great Society
    Jan 19: And now for the fat: Congress, foreign aid
    Jan 20: Who said we're pulling out of South Viet Nam?: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Jan 21: Successful launch: Lyndon B. Johnson
    Jan 22: A helluva way to run the World: United Nations, U. Thant
    Jan 25: Go out there and score, score, score!: Lyndon B. Johnson, Hubert Humphrey
    Jan 27: Presidential protection
    Jan 30: I believe it's your turn, again: Egypt, Congress, Gamal Abdel Nasser
  - Cartoons, 1965, Feb (Oversize 4)
    Feb 2: My move, comrade: Alexey Kosygin, Mao Zedong, Vietnam War
    Feb 3: Russian Winter: United Nations
    Feb 4: Scram...ain't you got no respect for private property?: voting rights, civil rights, Alabama
    Feb 5: Put up your dukes!: New York, Democratic Party
    Feb 6: Have boots, will travel: Lyndon B. Johnson, Latin America, Europe, Russia
    Feb 8: Sneaky counter punch!: Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War
    Feb 10: Commissar for spontaneous demonstrations against imperialistic American Embassy... speaking: Soviet Union
    Feb 11: Roundup: Lyndon B. Johnson
    Feb 12: Escalation: Vietnam War
    Feb 16: Show me an American student who enjoys such freedom of expression: students, demonstrations
    Feb 17: [Egyptian invite to East Germany]: Gamal Abdel Nasser, Ludwig Erhard, Israel
    Feb 18: In Mississippi we don't tolerate crimes like lettin' Negroes vote!: civil rights
    Feb 22: Yes, Mr. President...We're on the ball: Vietnam War, Maxwell Taylor
    Feb 23: Home to roost: violence, Malcolm X
    Feb 24: Tenderfoot: Lyndon B. Johnson, foreign policy
    Feb 26: Same rug, same salesman: Germany, Ludwig Erhard, Gamal Abdel Nasser, Walter Ulbricht
    Feb 27: Kosygin's great legs forward: Alexey Kosygin, Korea, Vietnam War
  - Cartoons, 1965, Mar (Oversize 4)
    Mar 1: Mississippi mud: justice, civil rights
    Mar 5: Ah, comrade....I see you're studying political science at Moscow University
    Mar 5: Did someone mention my name...again?: Richard Nixon
    Mar 9: The master race: Alabama, police, George Wallace
    Mar 10: Cheese it....it's the President: crime
    Mar 12: Mis-guided tour of the White House: demonstrations
    Mar 17: Hey, what ya doin' with my prisoner?: voting rights, racism, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Mar 18: If it's the last thing I do....I'm gonna hold back this dawn: voting rights, white supremacy
    Mar 20: I don't see anything 'bout voting rights for Negroes: U.S. Constitution, voting rights
    Mar 22: Toward the promised land: Alabama, civil rights
    Mar 23: I yell for states rights and you scream for federal intervention, see?: George Wallace
    Mar 27: Cancer cell: Ku Klux Klan
    Mar 30: ...and tell him we only call at night: Ku Klux Klan
    Mar 31: War...or whatever McNamara calls this...is hell!: Vietnam War
  - Cartoons, 1965, Apr (Oversize 4)
    Apr 1: We've changed from leave the driving to us to let Kosygin put you in the driver's seat: Alexey Kosygin, Soviet Union
    Apr 1: The Marines have escalated: Vietnam War
    Apr 2: What's your hurry? We've only had 100 years to talk this over: Congress, voting rights
    Apr 3: Checkpoint Marty: Alabama, Martin Luther King, Jr.
    Apr 7: Stop the World...I'm getting off!: Medicare
    Apr 9: Choice: Vietnam War
    Apr 10: What nerve...trying to bribe us with peace!: Vietnam War, Mao Zedong, Ho Chi Minh
    Apr 23: He's finally found his niche: college students, Vietnam War, demonstrations
    Apr 24: One of us is a tattletale gray: Federal Bureau of Investigation, Ku Klux Klan
    Apr 25: Scram! Can't you see we're busy hoarding: defense industry
  - Cartoons, 1965, May (Oversize 5)
    May 1: Plugmanship: Vietnam War, Dominican Republic, Lyndon B. Johnson
    May 15: Au revoir: France, Charles De Gaulle
    May 22: Where there's life there's hope: Dominican Republic
  - Cartoons, 1965, Jun (Oversize 5)
    Jun 5: Sucker vines: taxes, cotton industry
  - Cartoons, 1965, Jul (Oversize 5)
    Jul 3: Darn Road Block!: New York City, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Jr.
    Jul 22: What do you say we keep this a quiet issue: civil rights, Lyndon B. Johnson, Barry Goldwater
  - Cartoons, 1965, Aug (Oversize 5)
    Aug 11: Greek ruin: Greece
    Aug 13: Yes, Betty, a tree grew in Brooklyn.... that is, before the water crisis: New York City, natural resources
    Aug 21: Aawoooooooooooooo…: Gerald Ford, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Aug 31: G'wan to the showers, Casey!: Casey Stengel, New York Mets
  - Cartoons, 1965, Sep (Oversize 5)
    Sep 2: Steady as she goes: Dominican Republic
    Sep 3: Are you thinking what I'm thinking?: Russia, China, Pakistan, India
    Sep 10: Sick, sick, sick: Vietnam War, India, Pakistan
    Sep 13: DeGaulle re-examines Nato: Charles De Gaulle, NATO
  - Cartoons, 1965, Oct (Oversize 5)
    Oct 26: A treat: UNICEF, Nobel Peace Prize
    Oct 29: Come clean....did you pad your expense account?: Ku Klux Klan, House Un-American Activities Committee
    Oct 30: Everrrything iiis underrr cccontrol: Sukarno, Indonesia
  - Cartoons, 1965, Nov (Oversize 5)
    Nov 2: Witness: Ku Klux Klan
    Nov 3: Splat: Mao Zedong, Indonesia
    Nov 5: Why?...because it's there: Japan, Mao Zedong, trade
    Nov 5: Only DeGaulle can fill DeGaulle's shoes: Charles De Gaulle
    Nov 6: Patchwork: Vietnam War, economy
    Nov 9: Who are you calling black?: Lyndon B. Johnson, aluminum industry
    Nov 10: Independence: Rhodesia
    Nov 11: Dig we must: power failure
    Nov 12: We've freed ourselves from British bonds: Rhodesia, Ian Smith
    Nov 13: Filter system: Laos, Cambodia, Vietnam War
    Nov 15: What body: racial violence
    Nov 16: Was this trip necessary?: ship disaster
    Nov 17: Here comes another paper tiger: Vietnam War
    Nov 19: Say, chief...I think we're on the wrong show: Robert McNamara, Dean Rusk, Lyndon B. Johnson, peace
    Nov 20: Howdy, pardner: business, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Nov 22: Tight little island: Rhodesia
    Nov 26: Boom: War on Poverty, Sargent Shriver
    Nov 27: France's first satellite: Charles De Gaulle
    Nov 30: Suspended animation: Vietnam War. Ho Chi Minh
  - Cartoons, 1965, Dec (Oversize 5)
    Dec 2: Fill'er up? Didn't I a minute ago?: Vietnam War, Great Society, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Dec 4: Eye Opener: racial violence
    Dec 6: Hey, I didn't turn in any alarm!: inflation
    Dec 8: Tinderbox: Watts riot
    Dec 11: Famine – overpopulation – war: India
    Dec 13: My Kingdom for a screwdriver: space exploration
    Dec 14: At least I don't have to look at it all the time: John Birch Society
    Dec 15: I guess it's time for a new DeGaulle: Charles De Gaulle, elections
    Dec 17: Ever hear of Viet Nam?: Vietnam War, Great Society
    Dec 17: Head of state: Sukarno, Indonesia
    Dec 20: We ain't buying!: Mao Zedong, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam War
    Dec 23: I now change you into a first class citizen: Frank Boykin, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Dec 27: For a moment I thought I was coming in on a wing and a prayer: Vietnam War, Christmas
  - Cartoons, 1965, no date (Oversize 5)
    1965: The Champ: space exploration
    1965: Banner Headlines: Watts riots, Russia, China
    1965: From Russia with Love: space exploration, Russia
  - Cartoons, 1966, Jan (Oversize 5)
    Jan 3: No wheels!: transportation, New York City, John Lindsay
    Jan 4: How do you like your rice, comrade...one lump or two?: Fidel Castro, China, Cuba
    Jan 7: Uncle Sam wants you!: Bobby Baker
    Jan 8: Come to Poppa!: Russia, Ho Chi Minh, China, Alexey Kosgyin
    Jan 13: The great balancing act of '66: Great Society, Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Jan 15: Remember before the peace offensive, when this pacification was called a search and kill mission?: Vietnam War
    Jan 18: Sir, couldn't I go to Viet Nam instead?: War on Poverty, Sargent Shriver, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Jan 21: Fifteen Men on the dead man's chest- yo ho ho, and a bottle of rum: probate court, wills
    Jan 22: We're not admitting any nosy outsiders!: Congress, Central Intelligence Agency
    Jan 24: No bombing lull: population
    Jan 25: Onward and upward: Congress, budget
    Jan 28: Mind if I hitch a ride?: cost of living
    Jan 29: Can't hear a word you're saying: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Jan 30: Baker's Disaster: Bobby Baker
  - Cartoons, 1966, Feb (Oversize 5)
    Feb 2: Got any ideas?: Vietnam War, United Nations, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Feb 3: Groundhog Day: India, famine
    Feb 5: Why?...because it's there!: Vietnam War
    Feb 8: Chino go home: China, Cuba, Fidel Castro
    Feb 10: Let us put you in the Kamakaze seat: auto industry
    Feb 12: Peace- full nightmare: stock market
    Feb 15: Get out, they say: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Feb 18: carving knife: Fulbright hearings
    Feb 19: Into darkest Viet Nam: Vietnam War, Southeast Asia, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Feb 22: Easy on the goodies: labor, business
    Feb 26: That's gratitude...after all I've done for myself: Kwame Nkrumah
    Feb 28: My good right hand: Lyndon B. Johnson, Hubert Humphrey
  - Cartoons, 1966, Mar (Oversize 5)
    Mar 3: Impressionists: Robert McNamara, Dean Rusk, China
    Mar 4: Ahmed Sékou Touré, Guinea, Kwame Nkrumah, Ghana
    Mar5: Nobody loves me: Ernie Terrell, Cassius Clay (Muhammad Ali)
    Mar 8: Ping-pong: wages, prices
    Mar 9: ...And you can't throw me out of here!: Casey Stengel
    Mar 12: Hubert, what's this talk about you needing a new home?: Lyndon B. Johnson, Hubert Humphrey
    Mar 14: All I want is a sphere of influence: Mao Zedong
    Mar 15: I found this in your cabinet: John Diefenbaker, Lester Bowles Pearson
    Mar 16: Loss of stature: Sukarno
    Mar 17: Still active: Watts
    Mar 18: Another perfect docking: space exploration
    Mar 22: The poverty program: consumers, inflation
    Mar 24: Welcome to the do it yourself club: NATO, Mao Zedong, Charles De Gaulle
    Mar 25: Americans in trouble too...Los Angeles lost without Koufax and Drysdale: Vietnam War, sports
    Mar 28: Say your prayers: Buddhists, Vietnam War, Nguyen Cao Ky
    Mar 29: I'm still the leader!: Sukarno
    Mar 30: Madame, I'm happy to inform you it isn't steel: consumers, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Mar 31: This may call for a bit more withholding: inflation, Lyndon B. Johnson
  - Cartoons, 1966, Apr (Oversize 6)
    Apr 5: Reins of Government: Vietnam, Nguyen Cao Ky
    Apr 6: Oh say can you see?: UFOs
    Apr 7: First, we buckle up the government: auto industry
    Apr 9: Warning shot: Federal Drug Administration, drug industry
    Apr 11: They want to take away our freedom: Ian Smith, Rhodesia, Britain
    Apr 12: The high, hard pitch: inflation
    Apr 13: Wrong Ky: Lyndon B. Johnson, Vietnam War, Nguyen Cao Ky
    Apr 15: You wouldn't dare: anti-trust, baseball
    Apr 16: Remember when I was the adviser?: Vietnam War, casualties
    Apr 18: Anybody Home? No!: China, Dean Rusk, Mao Zedong
    Apr 19: Chief, the natives are restless: Lyndon B. Johnson, War on Poverty, Sargent Shriver
    Apr 21: Why don't you watch where I'm going!: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson, Gerald Ford, Everett Dirksen
    Apr 22: I solemnly swear to accept tax-free money: Christopher Dodd
    Apr 23: They're trying to make us freedom fighters look bad!: racism, armed forces
    Apr 29: Pin cushion: Vietnam War
    Apr 30: Hubert, don't pay any mind to people who say you don't sound like your old self: Lyndon B. Johnson, Hubert Humphrey
  - Cartoons, 1966, May (Oversize 6)
    May 2: Stay out of my territory...the sky!: Vietnam War
    May 3: What shall it be...self denial or surgery?: business, taxes, Lyndon B. Johnson
    May 6: Don't go away, folks...Congressman Ford isn't finished yet: Gerald Ford, Republican Party
    May 7: Re-entry: stock market
    May 9: At least when you were emperor you didn't: Charles De Gaulle, Napoleon
    May 14: Caution: inhaling may be hazardous to your health: pollution
    May 17: Using their heads: Nguyen Cao Ky, Buddhists
    May 19: Escalation: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    May 24: Runaway: cost of living
    May 25: Inside McNamara: peace, Robert McNamara
    May 27: Are you sure you have no nosy reporters to declare, Senator?: Robert F. Kennedy, South Africa
    May 30: Perpetual motion: Richard Nixon
  - Cartoons, 1966, Jun (Oversize 6)
    Jun 1: Puff, puff, toot, toot...: Fidel Castro, Guantanamo Bay
    Jun 2: Peace pipe: Buddhists, Nguyen Cao Ky
    Jun 3: No soft landing: Everett Dirksen, Gerald Ford, War on Poverty
    Jun 4: Of course I'm happy...I think: Lyndon B. Johnson, Dominican Republic, elections, Joaquín Balaguer
    Jun 11: [Editors: no caption with this cartoon.]: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Jun 13: I've been hunting those tremendous headlines in South Africa...what have you been doing lately?: Lyndon B. Johnson, Hubert Humphrey, Robert F. Kennedy
    Jun 15: Whatsamatter...aintcha heard of Miranda versus Arizona?: Supreme Court
    Jun 16: You know the rules...no gouging, no butting, no rabbit punching: Medicare, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Jun 22: It says here this model needs a complete overhaul: auto industry
    Jun 24: Here goes...: Christopher Dodd
    Jun 25: Oh that...that's the Capitol: Congress, Everett Dirksen, Hubert Humphrey, John McCormack
    Jun 27: Those damn Romanians don't know which end is up!: Chou En-lai, Romania, Mao Zedong
    Jun 28: Hot seat: Christopher Dodd
  - Cartoons, 1966, Jul (Oversize 6)
    Jul 1: Tiger in his tank: Robert F. Kennedy
    Jul 1: I remember when the fourth of July was called Independence Day: traffic
    Jul 2: Black Power: liberals, militants
    Jul 6: Of course, there's no longer a life time guarantee with the nameplate: Sukarno
    Jul 7: Dis-Chord: Soviet Union, Romania
    Jul 12: But on the other hand McNamara says we got plenty of fight: Lyndon B. Johnson, Vietnam War
    Jul 13: The best Defense Secretary is a good Offense Secretary: Robert McNamara
    Jul 14: They never touched us: Virginia election, Harry F. Byrd, Jr
    Jul 15: Escalation: weather
    Jul 16: Is ttthere a bbbbomb diposal expert in the hhhhouse?: Syria, Israel
    Jul 18: There ain't room enough for both of us!: white racism, black racism
  - Cartoons, 1966, Aug (Oversize 6)
    Aug 11: Pilot to tower...how do we get this off the ground?: airline industry, strikes
    Aug 12: Madame, consider yourself lucky...you ought to see the way they drive in Germany, Britain, France, etc.: inflation, cost of living
    Aug 13: I've decided to strike out on my own: North Korea, China
    Aug 15: Port of no call: Lyndon B. Johnson, wages, prices
    Aug 19: Slow down, please: credit
    Aug 24: Read all about it: cost of living
    Aug 25: The guns of August: Richard Nixon
    Aug 30: Go get him, Dick...he can't hurt us!: Barry Goldwater, Richard Nixon
  - Cartoons, 1966, Sep (Oversize 6)
    Sep 2: Anesthesia: urban problems
    Sep 7: Bread and butter play: Democratic Party, elections, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Sep 8: Somehow, Ev, with you I feel safe: Everett Dirksen, housing, civil rights
    Sep 9: That oughta hold him!: inflation, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Sep 12: Blacklash: black power, Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee
    Sep 13: We were ambushed at the polls: elections, Ho Chi Minh
    Sep 14: [Editors: No caption with this cartoon]: Mississippi, civil rights
    Sep 15: Lost in Space: prices, wages
    Sep 17: Racist!: Adam Clayton Powell
    Sep 20: He does too love me the most: Hubert Humphrey, Robert F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Sep 21: Overkill: auto industry, inflation
    Sep 24: Clay pigeon: Soviet Union, peace
    Sep 30: White Power: Georgia, elections, civil rights
    Sep: The Snipers: Warren Commission
  - Cartoons, 1966, Oct (Oversize 6)
    Oct 3: See...the door isn't shut completely: Vietnam War, Arthur Goldberg, Ho Chi Minh
    Oct 4: Congressman Weltner's got his nerve quittin our team: Lester Maddox, Georgia
    Oct 5: Sorry I'm a little late, Barry: Barry Goldwater, Dwight Eisenhower, crime, Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Oct 6: No, no, Miss Johnson, we've dropped that togetherness thing!: Lyndon B. Johnson, McCall's magazine
    Oct 8: [Editors: No caption with cartoon]: Lyndon B. Johnson, Asia
    Oct 11: Beat it, Carmichael...you're giving our outfit a bad image: Adam Clayton Powell, Stokely Carmichael, black power
    Oct 17: Out of the way...you 2,517 year old bourgeois revolutionist!: China, Confucius, communism
    Oct 18: It's a dove...it's a hawk...: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Oct 19: You run along...I'll take care of her: Congress, redwoods
    Oct 20: There will be no peace prize for 1966
    Oct 24: Halloween, 1966: elections, civil rights
    Oct 26: Surrender, or I'll cut you adrift: Gibralter, Francisco Franco
    Oct 29: New Buddha: Lyndon B. Johnson
    Oct: Today Bavaria...tomorrow, the world!: Nazism
  - Cartoons, 1966, Nov (Oversize 7)
    Nov 2: I have returned!: Lyndon B. Johnson, Democratic Party, Republican Party, elections
    Nov 4: I'm taking you out of the game!: Lyndon B. Johnson, Democratic Party, elections
    Nov 5: Hey Lyndon...you're supposed to be sick!: Lyndon B. Johnson, Richard Nixon
    Nov 7: What makes him think I'm watching?: Lyndon B. Johnson, Richard Nixon
    Nov 8: Uneasy lies the head that wears a crown: Germany, Ludwig Erhard
    Nov 9: Did you ever see an elephant fly?: Republican Party, elections
    Nov 11: Delivery problems: Congress, Great Society, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Nov 12: How's that for progress?: anti-missile systems
    Nov 17: I'm doing great...how about you?: Lyndon B. Johnson, presidential succession
    Nov 18: The fugitive: Adam Clayton Powell
    Nov 19: Next year I may have to use my other foot: United Nations, China, Arthur Goldberg
    Nov 25: Limited war: War on Poverty, Sargent Shriver, Congress
    Nov 29: Follow that car!: holidays, traffic fatalities
    Nov: Hold it...I got something to pep you up: economy, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Nov: Honestly, I can't imagine what people did before TV: television strike
  - Cartoons, 1966, Dec (Oversize 7)
    Dec 6: Step on it...he's widening the credibility gap!: press, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Dec 7: We shall continue our fight for freedom!: Ian Smith, Rhodesia
    Dec 8: Me again: Vietnam War